【翻译】巴蛮子sz
【时间轴】巴蛮子sz
【校对】巴蛮子sz
The Tenth Planet
Doctor Who 1963 04x02 (whopix fan edit)
神秘博士老版 第四季第二集 第十行星 （粉丝剪辑版）
（注意: 本字幕不针对原版视频，而是针对 Whopix 粉丝剪辑版本 http://wp.me/p1mHFo-1b8）
Man, it's blowing like crazy out there. All I can see is snow, snow and more snow.
呀，外面风吹得太吓人了．我唯一能看见的是雪，除了雪还是雪
Quite an arctic storm blowing out there. Hmm! Come along Polly, my child, with my cloak.
外面刮着很强烈的极寒风暴．嗯，快来，Polly，孩子，带上我的斗篷
Hey Doctor, you've got the most fantastic wardrobe!
哈，博士，你的衣橱是最神奇的
Yes, well I'm glad you approve my child.
是的，我很高兴你赞同我的观点，孩子
These are gorgeous. Where do you shop, Carnaby street?! Ha ha!
它们太棒了．你都在哪儿买的，Carnaby 街吗？哈哈！
Who do you think you are, Nanook of the North or something?!
你觉得你像谁，北方的纳努克怎么样？!
(备注: Nanook of the North 是1992年无声记录片，记录了北极圈内的原住民纳努克家族艰苦的生活）
Oh now, now, now. Tcha, tcha, tcha. Stop being so flippant.
哦快快快，去去去，别这么轻浮了
We don't know what we are in for outside there. Now come along, come along, come along.
我们不知道到外面会碰到什么．快来吧，来吧，来吧
Here you are, Doctor.
这是你的，博士
Are you sure you're going to be warm enough?
你确定这样够暖和？
Oh, like toast my dear. Now, did you find everything you want?
噢，就像吐司面包一样，亲爱的．你都找到你想要的没有？
Yes thanks!
是的，谢谢
All right, well let's go outside and investigate. Go along.
好了，我们出去看看情况吧，快来
The Doctor was right about this being the coldest place on earth. I'm freezing already.
博士说对了，这地方的确是地球上最冷的地方．我已经冻死了
Yeah.
是啊
Hey, what's this?
嗨，这是什么？
Well watch it Polly!
注意点 Polly !
It's some kind of an aerial. There must be something buried underneath there.
这是某种天线．这下面肯定有什么东西
Hey, look over there, there's something moving.
嗨，看那儿，有什么东西在移动
Hey Tito, will you come over here?
嘿 Tito，过来一下好吗？
Oh, what is it?
哦，什么事？
Come over here quick! I can see people!
到这里，快点！我可以看到人！
Sure, sure, lots of people!
当然，当然，好多人！
- And there's a woman!   - A woman...
- 还有一个女人！  - 女人...
A WOMAN! Hey!
一个女人！嘿！
Hey, hey! Mama Mia bellissima!
嘿，嘿！妈妈咪呀！
Looks... looks like some kind of a hut.
看起来像是一个小屋
Quick, take those small arms, get upstairs and get... bring them down. Get moving!
快，带上那些小武器，上去把他们带下来，动起来！
I think we'd better go with 'em.
我觉得我们还是跟他们走吧
Move it, come on, hurry it up, come on, let's go, let's go, come on pops,
动起来，来吧，快点，来，走了走了，快点小伙子
Will you move it, will you move it pops, let's go, come on!
动一动，动一动行吗，走了，快点！
Please stop that. Please, please stop that.
请别催了．求你了，别喊了
Just a moment pops. Now who are you, and what are you doing here?
等一下，你们都是谁，在这里做什么？
Oh, we just landed outside.
噢，我们刚刚在外面降落
- What in?  - Well it's a sort of spaceship actually.
- 坐的什么？  - 嗯，实际上是一种飞船
- Ha ha! Some spaceship, box!   - You can knock off the jokes.
- 哈哈！某种飞船，盒子吧！ - 你可以收起你的笑话
She's not joking.
她没开玩笑
Look buddy, I want the truth, and quick.
听着伙计，我要的是实话，快说
Can you tell us precisely where we are please?
你能否告诉我们这是什么地方？
You're at the South Pole base of international space command, and frankly pops...
你们在南极国际宇航指挥中心基地，坦白的说伙计...
Doctor.
博士
...Doctor, your story's gonna have to be awful good.
...博士，你的故事一定是极好的
So you mean we are on Earth?
你的意思是说我们在地球上？
Well you heard, the South Pole.
是啊你都听到了，是南极
Oh boy. Tito, get the CO.
哦小伙，Tito，去找CO
He's a-not going to like it.
他不会喜欢这个
Get him!
去叫他！
Why don't you speak up, I'm deaf!
你为什么不再大声点，我聋了！
Who's the CO?
CO 是谁？
The Commanding Officer, the boss.
就是指挥官，老大
Hallo... Sir? Er, Private Tito, duty guard here.
哈罗，长官．我是值班士兵 Tito
Could you give a message to the General please?
请问你可否给将军递个消息？
- General?  - General Cutler, the CO.
- 将军？  - Cutler 将军，指挥官
Sir? I know, but this is an emergency! What's that? The General's not there?
长官？我知道，但这是紧急情况！什么？将军不在那儿？
Well canna you tell me where he is then?
那你可以告诉我他在那里吗？
Right here, Private.
就在这里，士兵
What is it Sergeant?
中士那里去了？
Ah, well sir...
啊，这个...长官...
Who are these people?
这些人都是什么人？
Well sir, they just appeared outside.
长官，他们是突然出现在外面的
What?
什么？
Yes sir, as I said they just appeared, from a hut.
是的，长官，如我所说他们是突然出现的，从一个小屋子里
A hut?!
一个小屋子？
Yes sir. Never been there before.
是的长官，之前并不在那里
That's a right General. That's just the way it happened.
是那样的，将军，的确就是这么回事
Well? Who are you?
那么，你们是谁？
Able seaman Ben Jackson sir, Royal Navy.
水手Ben Jackson，隶属皇家海军，长官
Then why aren't you with your ship?
那你怎么不在你的船上？
That's a bit difficult to explain sir.
解释起来有点困难，长官
Yeah, I'll bet my sweet life it is.
是啊，我拿我甜美的生活打赌是
We don't intend you any harm General, I can assure you of that.
我们没有任何恶意，将军，我可以向你保证
You can assure me of what you like, but whether I'll believe you or not is another question.
你想怎么保证都行，但我相不相信你们就是另外一回事
Huh, huh!
哈，哈！
I haven't got time to deal with these now, but when I do you'd better have a good explanation.
我现在没时间管这事，但回头我有时间了你们最好能有一个好的解释
I don't like your tone, sir.
我不喜欢你的语气，长官
And I don't like your face, nor your hair!
我也不喜欢你的脸，你的头发
Hmm!
哼！
Sergeant, bring him into Tracking and put him under guard in the observation room.
中士，把他带到追踪处，把他置于观察室的看守之下
I'll deal with them as soon as I have time.
等我一有时间了就来处理他们这事
Yes sir!
是，长官！
OK, come on, move...
好，快点，移动...
Hey, this is smashing. It looks just like that rocket place in America.
嘿，这很惊人啊．看起来跟那种美国火箭发射的地方差不多
Yeah, but I wonder why there are so few people.
是啊，不过我好奇为什么人那么少
I mean it's not like what you see on the telly, is it?
我是说并不像你在电视上看见的那样，是不？
I don't know what you see on your TV, son,
我不知道你在电视上看到的是怎样的，小子
but this is General Cutler's outfit. Come on, you'd better take a seat.
但这是 Cutler 将军的场所．过来，你们最好坐下
He don't like a lot of personnel, cuts down to the bare minimum and works them right into the ground.
他不喜欢很多人员，削减到最低限度，把他们直接投入地下
We only spend a couple of months on this station anyway. We can't stand more than that.
反正我们只在这里待两三个月而已．我们没法忍受太久
Ha ha ha!
哈哈哈！
I see. Hey, perhaps we can catch a lift back to England.
明白了．嗨，也许我们还可以赶上个回英格兰的顺风车呢
Oh, I can't see the squire there giving us a free lift to anywhere.
哦，我看那位绅士不会让我们免费搭车去任何地方
Well I don't want to depress you both but I'm afraid we're not quite where you think we are.
我不想让你们俩郁闷，但恐怕我们并不完全是在你们想象的地方
- What do you mean?  - What?
- 什么意思？ - 什么？
Well, just take a peek at that. Huh huh! Hmm!
咯，瞥一眼那个去．哼哼！哼！
1986! Oh no, and I thought we'd be able to get home.
1986！不是吧，我还以为我们可以回家了呢
Yeah, we're still at sea. Here, but that'll explain the few people.
是，我们还在海上．对了，这就解释了为什么这么少人了
The computers must do all the work now. Here, I wonder if they got to the moon yet.
所有的工作现在肯定是电脑干．嗨，我好奇他们登上月球没有
Sure, don't you listen to the news?
当然．你们就不听新闻的吗？
You mean you have sent people to the moon?
你是说你们已经把人送上月球了？
Yeah, an expedition just returned.
当然，有支考察队刚回来
Well what's this flight then?
那这一次是飞哪儿？
Oh, this is just a normal atmosphere testing probe.
噢，这只是一个普通的大气测试探头
Yes, I see, a rocket testing site. Hum hum!
哦，明白了，一个火箭测试站，嗯嗯！
Hey, what's that?
嘿，那是什么？
An error? Where?
有错误？哪里？
Looks bad. We're now over south isle of New Zealand and reading a height of 1100 miles.
看起来不对，我们现在在新西兰南岛上空，高度数值是1100英里
1100? But that's impossible! Dyson, check what it should be, will you?
1100？那不可能啊！Dyson，检查设定值，好吗？
It should be 980.
设定值是980
No, it can't be, let me try.
不，不可能，我试试
Let me do it.
我来吧
No, you're right. 980 miles... they're out of position by more than a hundred miles!
不，你是对的，980英里...他们的位置偏了100多英里！
Mmm, looks like it.
嗯，看着像是
Snowcap to Zeus 4. Can you read me?
雪冠呼叫宙斯4号，你能听到吗？
Zeus 4 to Snowcap. Strength 8, over.
宙斯4号回复雪冠，强度为8．结束
Take visual checks on Mars to establish position. Report back.
参考火星进行目视检查，以确定位置，回报结果
Here we are. Well now, excuse me my dear...
好了．现在，打扰一下...
...er, take this to your General please.
...请把这个交给你们的将军
Me? Are you crazy?
我？你疯了吗？
Very well then, take me to the General. I think perhaps I can help him.
那好吧，带我去见将军．我想我可以帮上他
Oh I... I don't know.
噢...我不知道
Now look here Sergeant, this is urgent, I insist.
给我听着，中士，这事很紧急，我坚持
General, sir.
将军，长官
Yes, what is it?
嗯，什么事？
The old boy would like to have a word with you. Claims it's urgent.
这个老伙计想跟你说两句话，他说很紧急
OK, bring him over. But make it fast.
好，带他过来，不过动作要快
I think I know what you are going to see.
我想我知道你们将会看到什么
How can you possibly? Oh, get him back over there.
你怎么可能呢？噢，把他弄回那边去
I've written down here what he will see.
我已经写下了他将看到什么
Take your hands off me please!
请把你的手拿开！
Barclay! It's not very clear but it's a planet all right.
Barclay！这不是太清楚但应该是一颗行星
How could it be? Planets don't just appear.
这怎么可能？行星不可能就这么出现了
It must be on a weak orbit.
它肯定是在一个弱轨道上
It's approaching quite fast. Barclay, couldn't it be...
它正在快速接近．Barclay，它会不会...
I know what you're thinking. Zeus 4 is out of orbit and a new planet has appeared.
我知道你在想什么．宙斯4号偏离了轨道，又有一颗行星出现了...
Therefore the new planet is influencing Zeus 4. Right?
所以这颗行星会影响宙斯4号，对吧
That's about it.
就是这么回事
We must get them down!
我们必须把他们弄下来！
An emergency splash zone?
一个紧急溅射区域？
Yes. Snowcap calling Zeus 4, come in please. Zeus 4 come in please. Do you read me?
是．雪冠呼叫宙斯4号，请回话．宙斯4号请回话．你们能否听到？
Yes, we read you loud and clear.
听到，声音响亮而清晰
You are strength 2 only. Come in please, speak up.
你们的强度只有2级．请回话，大声点
Fuel cells are showing a power loss.
燃料电池显示有能量流失
Power loss?
能量流失？
Its gravity is affecting the capsule.
它的引力在影响太空舱
What shall we do about it?
我们怎么对付这个？
Well first of all we must give Zeus 4 a new correction path. Will you do that?
首先我们必须给宙斯4号一条修正路线，你能搞定吗？
Right away.
马上
You try and get a better fix on that so-called planet and see what it is.
你就尽力跟进那个所谓的行星，搞明白到底是个什么东西
Right sir.
是，长官
It's better now.
现在好点了
You say you know what this planet is. Well what is it?
你说你知道这个行星是什么，那它是什么？
Well I'm not quite sure sir. Let me have another look into this instrument.
呃我也不是太确定长官．我再去看一眼仪表
Feed the retina scope into the observations room's monitor.
把高清镜头的画面投到观察室的显示器上
Look Dr Barclay, let's just get those boys down.
Barclay 博士，我们去把那些小伙子弄下来
General, General, yes, it's just as I thought.
将军，将军，是的，的确如我所料
Come and have a look at these land masses.
过来看看这些大陆板块
Land masses? I don't see... I see what you mean.
大陆板块？我不明白...我明白你的意思了
Now, doesn't that remind you of anything, hmm?
现在，有没有想起一点什么？
Remind? No, I don't think so.
想起？不，我不觉得
Yeah, it looks familiar somehow.
是，这怎么看起来有点眼熟
Yeah. Hey Ben, look, that bit looks just like... Malaysia!
是啊，嘿 Ben，看，那块看起来像是...马来西亚
Oh, give over. No, hang on, isn't that... well it looks like South America but it can't be though!
哦，算了吧．不，等等，那不是...看起来像是南美洲，但这不可能啊！
Yes, there is a similarity.
的确，有一些相似性
Nonsense, how could there be?
胡说，怎么可能？
This is unbelievable. That's surely Africa?
这让人难以置信啊，那肯定就是非洲啰？
Yes, certainly and that is Malaysia!
是，那确定就是马来西亚
Ridiculous. There must be some reflection of Earth.
荒谬，肯定是某个地方反射出了地球的样子
No it can't be, there's nothing to reflect on!
这不可能，没有什么可反射的物质啊
And now my dear Dr Barclay I suggest you look at that piece of paper I gave you.
现在，亲爱的 Barclay 博士，我建议你看一下我给你的那张纸
Paper? Oh yes...
纸？噢，是的...
You knew!
你早知道！
Certainly.
当然
Knew what?
早知道什么？
He has correctly written down what we have just seen and he did it before we saw it.
他准确地写出了我们刚才看见的东西，但他是在我们看见之前写的
Oh, it's a... simple confidence trick, that's all.
哦，这是个...简单的障眼法，仅此而已
No, I know when he gave me the paper.
不，我知道他什么时候给我这张纸的
Now, you clearly know something more about the situation. Can you be more explicit?
对于当前的情况，你显然还知道些什么，你能说得更明白点吗
Yes sir, I'm sorry, I'm afraid I can.
是的先生，很抱歉，恐怕我能
You see, millions of years ago there was a twin planet to Earth and...
你知道吗，数百万年前，地球有一个孪生兄弟...
Oh, for heaven's sake!
噢，老天爷啊！
Roger, Zeus 4...
收到，宙斯4号...
Get me Geneva on the radio link.
给我接通日内瓦的无线电连接
We'll see what Wigner has to say about this.
我们看看 Wigner 对于这事有什么看法
You're looking terribly worried Doctor.
你看起来非常担心，博士
Am I my dear? Yes, I'm afraid I am rather worried.
是吗亲爱的？是的，恐怕我是真的担心
What is it Doctor? What's up?
是什么情况，博士？怎么了？
Well you see Ben, I know what this planet is and what it means to Earth.
哦你看 Ben，我知道这个星球是什么，对地球又意味着什么
And what does it mean to Earth?
对地球意味着什么？
Well, that pretty soon we shall be having visitors.
意味着，很快我们就会有客人来了
Now, suppose you tell me how you really came here.
现在，想来你可以告诉我，你实际上怎么来这里的
Yes, well I'm afraid all that's going to be rather difficult.
可以，只是恐怕那会相当困难
Now just a minute. You turn up out of nowhere, a routine space shot goes wrong...
等一等，你不知道从哪儿就钻出来了，例行的飞船发射出了问题...
a new planet appears and you tell us you know all about it. That puts you slap bang in the hot seat, right
一个新的行星冒出来了，你又说你对它很了解，fixme
Hot seat?
But we've got nothing to do with it.
但我们跟它没关系啊
That you're going to have to prove.
这个你们必须得证明
Well, I think if you allowed us to return where we came from, huh, huh! I...
我想如果你允许我们回到我们来的地方，呵，呵...
You're not going anywhere.
你那儿也别想去
- Sergeant?  - Yes sir?
- 中士？  - 什么事，长官？
- Have you searched that hut yet?  - No, sir
- 你们搜过那个小屋吗？ - 没有，长官
Well why not?! Look, I don't want any excuses, get out there and do it immediately.
为什么没有？我不想要任何借口，立即出去把这事办了
Now, perhaps we'll get to the bottom of this.
现在，也许我们可以得到这事的底细
Come on Tito, we have to go break into a hut.
来吧 Tito，我们必须得闯入那个小屋去
What, that thing out there?
什么，就那里那个东西？
Yeah, that's right. Come on, hurry up and get dressed up.
是的，就是这样．来吧，快点，穿上点
Oh, mama.
噢，妈呀
It's no good Tito, we'll need a welding torch to get inside this thing.
这没用的 Tito，我们要用焊枪才能进得去这里
Get back inside and bring me out one. You'll need some help, OK?
回到里面去，给我拿一个出来，找两个帮忙的，行吗？
Hurry up will ya, before I freeze to death!
快点行吗，要不然我要冻死了
What the heck? Huh, Tito! Is that you Tito?
什么鬼？啊，Tito！是你吗 Tito？
What's going on here? Who is that?
这里怎么回事？谁在那儿？
Who the heck are you?!
你到底是谁？
OK Joe, that should do it. OK, let's go.
好了 Joe，这应该可以了．好，我们走
Hey, this is where it is guys.
嘿，就是这个地方了伙计们
That's the most fantastic story I've ever heard.
这是我听过的最离奇的故事
I can only repeat, sir, what I have already told you.
先生，我只能重复一下我已经告诉过你的事情
You will get visitors from that other planet.
你会有来自那个星球的访客
Nonsense.
胡扯
It's imperative that I talk to you, General.
我必须和你谈谈，将军
Get away, old man. Can't you see...
走开，老头，你看不到...
You, will you pay attention? Will you?!
你，不能留点意吗？能吗？
Get this man back into the observations room. Sergeant, that was an order!
把这个人带到观察室去．中士，那是命令！
Take that man back to the obs...
把那个人带到观察...
Back to your places.
回到你们的岗位上去
Oh no...
噢，不
Come back Polly, they'll blow your head off!
回来 Polly，他们会轰掉你的脑袋的！
Now look, I don't know who you are or what you are
你看，我不知道你们是谁，是什么东西
but we've got two men in space, if we don't act now we won't get them back alive.
但我们有两个人还在太空，如果我们现在不行动他们就不能活着回来了
They will not return.
他们不会回来了
Why not?
为什么不能？
It is unimportant now.
现在不重要了
But... We must get them back! When...
但是...我们必须把他们弄回来！等到...
There is really no point. They could never reach Earth now.
这真的没有意义，他们现在再也到不了地球了
But don't you care?
但你们不在乎吗？
Care? No, why should I care?
在乎？不，我为什么要在乎？
Because they're people and they're going to die!
因为他们是人，而他们要死了！
I do not understand you. There are people dying all over your world...
你也不在乎他们
...yet you do not care about them.
...你也不在乎他们
Yes, but we could avoid their deaths...
是，但我们可以避免这两个人的死...
You will be wondering what has happened.
你会想知道发生了什么事
Your astronomers will have just discovered a new planet. Is that not so?
你们的天文学家刚刚发现了一颗新行星，不是这样吗？
Yes, that's right.
对，是这样
That is where we come from. It is called Mondas.
那是我们来的地方，它叫做 Mondas
Mondas?
Mondas? But isn't that one of the ancient names of Earth?
Mondas? 但是那不是地球的其中一个古名吗？
Yes. Aeons ago our planets were twins then we drifted away from you...
是的．很久以前咱们的行星是双胞胎，然后我们就离开了你们...
...on a journey to the edge of space. Now we have returned.
...去往了宇宙的边缘．现在我们回来了
You were right, Doctor.
你说对了，博士
But who or what are you?
但你们是谁？是什么？
We are called Cybermen.
我们叫做赛博人
Cybermen?
赛博人
Yes, Cybermen. We were exactly like you once
是的，赛博人．以前我们跟你们完全一样
but our cybernetic scientists realised that our race was getting weak.
但我们的控制论科学家意识到我们的种族正在变得脆弱
Weak, how?
脆弱，怎么脆弱？
Our life span was getting shorter so our scientists and doctors
我们的寿命越来越短，所以我们的科学家和医生...
... devised spare parts for our bodies until we could be almost completely replaced.
......为我们的身体器官设计了备件，直到我们几乎全身被替换掉
But... that means you're not like us. You're robots!
但是...这就是说你们跟我们不一样，你们是机器人！
Our brains are just like yours except that certain weaknesses have been removed.
我们的大脑和你们的一样，只是某些弱点已经消除了
Weaknesses? What weaknesses?
弱点？什么弱点？
You call them emotions, do you not?
你们把它们叫做情感，是吗？
But... that's terrible! You... you mean you wouldn't care about someone in pain?
但是...那也太糟了! 你是说你们不会关系痛苦的人？
There would be no need. We do not feel pain.
没有这个必要，我们感觉不到痛苦
But we do.
但我们会
General!
将军！
Ha, that'll fix ya! Europe will know there's an emergency here now.
哈，可以修理你们了！欧洲会知道这里出了紧急状况
That was really most unfortunate. You should not have done that.
那可真是非常的不幸．你不应该干这个
Switch off the radio and tell Europe that nothing further has happened and that all is well here.
关掉无线电，告诉欧洲没什么事情发生，这里一切都好
I'll do no such thing.
我不干这样的事
That is an order.
这是命令
Go take a jump!
去跳脚吧！
Trigger pack.
（？）
Stay where you are.
待在原地别动
You've killed him!
你们杀了他！
I have not killed him. He will recover.
我没有杀他，他会恢复的
Now, someone must answer your commander in Europe. He is waiting.
现在，必须有个人回复你们的欧洲指挥官，他还在等着
I refuse.
我拒绝
You.
你
Yes?
怎样？
Which are the communication controls?
通讯开关是哪些？
O... over here.
在...在那边
Dyson!
Stand aside
站一边去
What are you going to do?
你打算做什么？
You will see.
你很快就会明白
If you destroy those we shall be unable to keep contact with the capsule.
如果你毁灭那些，我们就不能同太空舱保持联系了
Your commander is still waiting for your report.
你们的指挥官还在等你们的报告
For God's sake Barclay, do as he asks. Do you want the place destroyed?
上帝啊，Barclay，按他要求的做吧．你想让这个地方毁灭吗？
All right.
好吧
Come in Geneva.
请回话日内瓦
Snowcap. What's going on? We received an emergency from you on the radio link.
雪冠，什么情况？我们收到了你们通过无线电发出的紧急信号
I-i-i-it was a fault. We're, we are looking at it now. I'm sorry about the false alarm.
它它它是个故障．我们，我们现在正在检查．虚惊一场的事我很抱歉
Where is the static coming from? We can hardly hear you, even on this band.
刚才的沉寂是怎么回事，我们几乎听不到你们，就连这个频道也是
It it it, well, I-I-I, er think it must have been the reactor.
这这，呃，我，我想一定是反应堆的问题
We had the moderator on, er, for a time this afternoon and er, well, well that's probably it.
我们把慢化剂打开了，呃，开了一下午，呃，可能就是它
I see. Contact us if you have any further reports on this new planet.
我明白了．如果你们有那个新行星的进一步报告，联系我们
Yes sir.
好的先生
Well done, Barclay. Now the space capsule will have another chance.
做得好，Barclay．现在太空舱多了一个机会
Now you must let us try and get in touch with our astronauts.
现在你必须让我们尝试与我们的航天员联系
I told you it is impossible for them to get back now.
我告诉过你，他们现在不可能回得来
The force on them is too strong.
施加在他们那里的力量太强了
But you must let us try, please.
但你必须得让我们试试，求你了
It is a foregone conclusion. You are wasting time.
这已成定局．你在浪费时间
However, if you wish to contact them I have no objection.
然而，如果你想联系他们，我不反对
He and his colleagues may use their equipment.
他和他的同事可以使用他们的设备
Any attempt at deceit however, kill them at once.
然而，发现任何企图欺骗的情况，立即杀死他们
Remove the soldier. I will carry on detail.
移走这位士兵．我好展开细节
Snowcap to Zeus 4, come in please. Zeus 4, come in please.
雪冠呼叫宙斯4号，请回话，宙斯4号，请回话
We have you, over.
我们能听到，结束
Prepare to check orbital density.
准备检查轨道密度
Ready.
就绪
Right Doctor, while they take him out we'll make a break for it.
对，博士，他们抬他出去的时候，我们就冲出去
Then we can get back to the TARDIS!
那我们就可以回到 TARDIS 了
Well how can we do that, boy?
但我们怎么能做到呢，孩子？
Well, we can make a break for it. Down that corridor, the trapdoor and then bolt it from behind.
是，我们可以冲出去．穿过走廊，活板门，然后从后面锁上
Nonsense, nonsense, they'll burn it down in a flash!
胡说八道，胡说八道，他们会在一瞬间把它烧了!
We can do with that for a start!
我们可以拿这个开场！
No, Ben!
别，Ben！
If they see you... Ben, for goodness sake!
如果他们看到见你... Ben，看在上帝的份上！
Stop! Come here.
停下！过来
You do not seem to take us seriously.
看来你没把我们当回事啊
Blimey!
啊呀！
Heavens!
老天！
Take him out and look after him.
带他出去，看好他
It is quite useless to resist us. We are stronger
抵抗我们是完全没有用的．我们更强壮
and more efficient than your Earth people. We must be obeyed.
也比你们地球人更有效率．必须服从我们
Uh! Locked... uh! No
啊，锁上了...啊，不
What happened?
发生了什么？
I'm afraid the spaceship exploded, my dear.
恐怕是太空船爆炸了，亲爱的
You mean they're dead?
你是说他们死了？
Now perhaps you can see that your planet is in great and imminent danger.
现在也许你可以看到，你的星球正处于巨大的危险之中，而且迫在眉睫
In order to save you we shall require information to be transmitted to Mondas.
为了拯救你们，我们将要求将信息传送到 Mondas
Save us?
拯救我们？
What about those poor men?
那些可怜的人怎么办？
Perhaps you will co-operate. Mondas drew the ship away. It was unavoidable.
也许你们会合作．Mondas 的引力把船拖走了．这是不可避免的．
Why? What is happening?
为什么？发生了什么事情？
I will require your name.
我要你的名字
Tell us!
告诉我们！
The energy of Mondas is nearly exhausted
Mondas 的能量已经基本耗尽
and now we turn to it's twin and will gather energy from Earth.
现在我们向它的孪生兄弟寻求帮助，将从地球收集能量
Gather energy?!
收集能量？！
Age, name and occupation.
年龄，姓名和职业
But for how long?
要多久？
My name is John Dyson, supervising engineer.
我的名字是 John Dyson，主管工程师
Until it is all gone. Age.
直到它消失．年龄
But that means that the Earth will... will die!
但那就意味着地球将会...将会死亡！
Yes. Everything on Earth will stop. Age please.
是的．地球上的一切都会停止．请报上年龄
But you can't calmly stand there and tell us we're all going to die!
但你们不能就静静地站在那里，然后告诉我们我们都会死!
You are not going to die.
你们不会死
And how are you going to stop this energy drain from Mondas?
那你们打算怎么阻止 Mondas 抽取能量呢？
Name and occupation please. We cannot. It is beyond our powers.
请提供姓名和岗位．我们不能．这超过我们的能力了
How are we going to survive?!
那我们怎么能活下去？
Speak please. By coming with us. Age.
请说．跟我们一起走．年龄
With you?
跟你们？
Yes. We are going to take you all back to Mondas. Your age please.
是的．我们打算带你们所有人回到 Mondas．请报上年龄
- His age is unimportant here!
- That's the most ridiculous thing I've ever heard in my life!
- 他的年龄现在不重要！  - 这是我这辈子听过最扯淡的事情！
You cannot for one moment...
你不能一会儿...
Hey, wait a minute! If I was to turn this on the door...
嘿，等一下！如果我把这个转过来朝向门...
...it might blind him! Yeah.
...可能可以晃瞎他！嘢
Hah! I saw that film 20 years ago.
哈！我20年前看过这个电影
Oy, come in here mate, you're wanted! Oy, come in here!
噢，进来吧伙计，需要你！噢，进这里来吧
Blemmy ehny ah fu! Uh!
Now then, Fred!
开动，Fred！
Ahh!
啊！
Do not resist. Give me that weapon.
不要反抗．把那个武器给我
No, I'm sorry mate, I'm giving the orders here. Now look, get back.
不，抱歉伙计，是我话事了．现在，退后
Look, I'm telling you, get back!
看，我告诉你，退后！
You didn't give me no alternative!
你没有别的办法了！
There's no scientific certainty that this is a dying planet!
没有任何科学理论能推论出这个星球肯定要死亡了
Perhaps we would prefer to take our chances here.
也许我们应该选择碰碰运气
You must come and live with us.
你们必须来，跟我们一起生活
But we cannot live with you, you're... you're different, you've got no feelings.
但我们不能跟你们一起．你们是...不一样的，你们没有感受
Feelings? I do not understand that word.
感受？我不懂那个词
Emotions. Love, pride, hate, fear. Have you no emotions, sir?
情感．爱，恨，骄傲，恐惧．你们没有情感吗，先生？
Come to Mondas and you will have no need of emotions.
到 Mondas 来吧，你们就不需要情感了
You will become like us.
你们会变成我们这样
Like you?
你们这样？
We have freedom from disease, protection against heat and cold, true mastery.
我们有免于疾病的自由，不怕冷和热，真正地做主
Do you prefer to die in misery?
你们更愿意悲催地死去？
But look, surely I... it's possible for us not to lose Earth's energy?
但是你看，当然我...是否有可能不要让地球失去能量？
It is inevitable.
这不可避免
Then you don't mind if we all die.
那你们就不在乎我们全都死掉？
Why should we mind?
为什么我们要在乎？
Why? Why?!
为什么，为什么？
Because millions and millions of people are going to suffer and die horribly!
因为数万数万万的人会受苦，并且痛苦地死去！
We shall not be affected.
我们不会收到影响
Don't you think of anything except yourselves?!
除了你们自己，你们就不考虑其它任何事吗？
We are equipped to survive. We are only interested in survival. /
我们换这些装备目的是为了存活．我们感兴趣的也只有存活
Anything else is of no importance. Your deaths will not affect us.
其它事情都不重要，你们的死亡对我们没有影响
But I can't make you understand, you're condemning us all to die, have you no heart?
我怎么就跟你们说不明白，你们这是在搞死我们，你们就没有心吗？
No, that is one of the weaknesses that we have removed.
没有，那是弱点之一，我们已经移除掉了
All right, get me Geneva, quick!
好吧，给我接日内瓦，快！
Come on, let's have some action. Get rid of these... things!
快点，我们得有所行动．得干掉这些...家伙！
I don't think you should have done that, General. We may have learned a very great deal.
我觉得你不应该那么干，将军．我们本可能了解到很多东西
Yeah, we may have lost a very great deal, our lives!
是，我们本可能失去很多东西，我们的性命！
Missile control? Program all Cobra anti-missiles for launch imminent.
导弹控制中心吗？部署所有眼镜蛇反导弹，准备立即发射
Stand in readiness and await instructions.
随时准备，等待指示
- What a ghastly man.
- Yeah, I wouldn't want him on the bridge.
- 真是个可怕的人   - 是，我可不希望他在舰桥上
We'll soon have this place sealed up like a bottle.
我们很快就会把这个地方像瓶子一样封起来
I think you rather underestimate the Cybermen, General.
我觉得你严重低估了赛博人，将军
Oh, that's what you reckon is it, old man?
哦，那是你的估计吧，老头？
Well, you're entitled to your opinions so long as you keep them to yourself!
是，你有权给出意见，只要你把它们留在你自己这里
General Cutler, sir!
Cutler 将军，长官！
Yes, what is it?
嗯，什么事？
Strong signal on the early warning, unidentified.
出现强烈预警信号，尚未具体识别
Well, identify it, man!
那就赶紧识别，伙计！
Yes sir, it's er, er... There are hundreds of them, sir!
是的，长官，这是...他们有几百个，长官
Hundreds of what, man?
几百个什么，伙计？
Spaceships sir. In formation!
太空船，长官．正在集结！
Spaceships. That means only one thing, more Cybermen.
太空船．那只意味着一件事：更多的赛博人
Dyson, see if you can get hold of Zeus 5, I want to speak to my son.
Dyson，看看能否接通宙斯5号，我要跟我儿子通话
Trying now, sir.
正在联系，长官
What's the matter, Doctor?
你怎么啦，博士？
Doctor, what's the matter?
博士，怎么回事？
Dyson, get through to Zeus 5!
Dyson，接通宙斯5号！
What's happened to you, Doctor?
你怎么了，博士？
I'm not sure, my dear. Comes from an outside influence.
我也不太确定，亲爱的．是外界来的影响
Unless this old body of mine is wearing a bit thin.
除非我的旧身体换上一身新皮
What do you mean "wearing a bit thin"?
什么意思？“换上一身新皮”？
Oh, don't worry child, don't worry, don't worry...
喔，别担心孩子，别担心，别担心...
Silence. Anyone who moves will be killed instantly.
安静．谁再动就格杀勿论
Your planet is finished. It will disintegrate. We know why you came here./?
你的星球完蛋了．它将会碎掉．我们知道你们为什么来这里
So why not stay and live with us in peace, hmm?
所以为什么不坐下来，与我们和平相处呢，嗯？
We cannot talk while that missile is aimed at Mondas. It must be disarmed first.
如果导弹还对着 Mondas, 我们不能和谈．必须先把它卸掉．
A moment, please.
请等一下．
Are you able to disarm this rocket?
你们能够将火箭解除武装吗？
Well, yes - but...
哦，可以 - 不过．．．
It will give us the time we need!
这可以帮我们争取时间，我们正需要这个！
The time for Mondas to burn itself out, you mean?
好让 Mondas 自己烧毁，是这意思吗？
Yes, now quiet! We accept your terms. The warhead will be removed from the rocket.
是的，安静！ 我们接受你们的条件，弹头将会从火箭上拆卸下来．
It must be removed to below ground level.
弹头必须移动到地下去．
Well, there's the Radiation Room. It's the deepest in the base.
这样，有个辐射室，是这个基地最深的地方．
That will do. And to make sure you do this, we will take two hostages.
那倒可以．为了确保你们能做到，我们将扣留两人做人质
That girl will go to the spacecraft.
那个女孩儿，到我们的飞船去
Surely you're not going to return to Mondas now?
你们这会儿不打算回到 Mondas 是吧？
We will not discuss our plans with you.
我们不会跟你们讨论我们的计划
What is your second objective? It's quite obvious, isn't it? The destruction of the Earth!
你们的第二目标是什么？ 昭然若揭了，对不对，就是要毁灭地球！
This close proximity of our two planets means that...
我们两个星球靠得太近...
one has to be eliminated for the safety of the other.
这意味着要保障其中一个的安全，就得毁灭另外一个
The one to be destroyed will be Earth. We cannot allow Mondas to burn up.
将被毁灭的是地球，我们不可能让 Mondas 烧毁
Take the old man out to the spacecraft.
将这个老人带出去，送进飞船
You will regret this.
你会后悔的
Doctor... Doctor?
博士...博士？
Hmm... What is it, child?
唔...怎么了，孩子？
Engines! They're not going to take off, are they?
引擎！他们不打算起飞，是吧？
No, no. Wait! The vibrations. Perhaps it's coming from Mondas!
不，不．等等！这个振动，也许是来自 Mondas!
What do you mean, Mondas?
Mondas? 什么意思？
This spacecraft receives its energy from Mondas. Perhaps it's absorbing too much.
这艘飞船是从 Mondas 接收能量的，可能它吸收得太多了
Don't mean it's going to blow up, do you?
是不是意味着它就要爆炸了，是吗？
No, I don't know, child. It is an unknown power...
我也不知道，孩子．这是一种未知的能量
Doctor, I'm scared!
博士，我害怕！
Just look at Mondas! I can't believe it!
快看 Mondas! 简直不敢相信
Fantastic! It looks as if it's melting!
太神了，看起来它在融化！
It's falling to bits!
正在裂成碎片！
The end of Mondas.
Mondas 的末日
Hey, look!
嘿，看！
What's happened to them?
他们怎么了？
They've disintegrated!
他们分解了！
They must have been entirely dependent on power from Mondas!
他们一定完全依靠 Mondas 提供能量
Doctor!
博士！
Ben! Oh please, Ben, help me... get me out of this thing!
Ben! 哦，请，Ben, 帮我一下．．．把我带出这里！
All right, don't panic, I'll have you out soon!
好的，别慌，我马上把你弄出去！
Ow! My hands were stuck and I couldn't get out!... Ben, I've been so scared!
哦！ 我的手卡住了，弄不出来！．．．Ben, 我很害怕
Take it easy love, take it easy.
放松点，放松点
And that Cyberman thing, it just fizzled into nothing, Ben, it was awful...
还有那些赛博人，突然全都消失了．Ben, 好可怕．．．
Now what's the matter with the Doctor?
博士这是怎么了？
I don't know. When the lights went out, he just seemed to faint.
我不知道．当灯熄灭的时候，他似乎晕过去了
Hey, come on Doctor, wakey wakey! It's all over now.
嘿，来吧博士，醒醒！ 都结束了
What did you say, my boy?
你说什么，孩子？
"It's all over. " That's what you said.
＂都结束了＂这是你说的
No... but it isn't all over. It's far from being all over.
不，还没都结束，还远没结束呢
Wait for us!
等等我们！
Open the door!
打开门！
Hey, let us in!
嘿，让我们进去！
You can't leave us here, of all places! Open up!
你不能把我们留着这里，留在那里也不行！打开！
Doctor!
博士!
Doctor! Quick, help him!
博士！快，帮忙他！
No, leave him!
不，别动他！